<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aesthetics of the Absurd</title>
    <link>https://9bladed.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aesthetics of the Absurd</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 15:30:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://9bladed.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Resources for Free Photography Software</title>
      <link>https://9bladed.com/post/foss_photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://9bladed.com/post/foss_photography/</guid>
      <description>A lizard pauses for a photo I took last year on a rafting trip in the Grand Canyon. [Flickr, 500px]
Whether you are a budding amateur or a seasoned professional photographer, the software tools you use play an important role in organizing, editing, and showing your photos. Maybe you are tired of continuing to pay Adobe as all their software moves to subscriptions or are looking for some of the best tools out there which also happen to be free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Side of Paris</title>
      <link>https://9bladed.com/photo-essay/paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://9bladed.com/photo-essay/paris/</guid>
      <description>[Something I&amp;rsquo;ve long been thinking about doing are photo stories or essays, combining a set of photos into a larger, more cohesive, work. This is my first attempt after recently taking a trip to Paris, one of my favorite cities. Comments welcome! Click on a photo to view it full size on Flickr, until I add some fancy gallery.]

As the train pulled into Gare du Nord and I took my first walk in Paris after many years, I was once again struck by the magic that I feel in only a few cities I have ever visited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Existential Crisis</title>
      <link>https://9bladed.com/essay/existential/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://9bladed.com/essay/existential/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After 5 years as a gradstudent and 5 years as a postdoc (researcher) in physics, my academic career has come to an end. This was not on my terms; I had come up short of my dream to be a tenured faculty member at a research university. I sold off what little furniture I had, packed up my few belongings, drove 1,000 miles (which turned out to be the end for the car) from the South back to the Northeast, and finally hopped on a plane to Europe. My current plan, if you can call it that, is only for a few months, to revive some dormant passion projects, in the hope of finding my path forward for whatever is next&amp;#x2026;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relaunch</title>
      <link>https://9bladed.com/post/relaunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://9bladed.com/post/relaunch/</guid>
      <description>Hi there.
Yet again (I&amp;rsquo;ve lost track of how many times) I am rebranding and relaunching my website. I would love to give some assurances (mostly to myself) that it is for good and will continue posting regularly, but I think I finally know enough to not make such promises. I am hopeful, though, mostly because of my current situation.
To put it briefly, since I plan on going into many details in later writings, my time as a theoretical physicist has come to a close.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>